good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to ICI Lombard General
Insurance company limiteds q1 fy2
earnings conference call from the Senior
Management we have with us today Mr
sanjie mantri MD and CEO of the company
Mr gopal balachandran
CFO Mr Alo Agarwal executive director Mr
Girish nyak Chief technology and health
underwriting and claims Mr s Goradia
Chief corporate solutions group Mr Anand
singi Chief retail and government
business and Mr gorov Aurora Chief
underwriting and claims underwriting and
claims Property and
Casualty please note that any statements
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to their management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involved risks and
uncertainities which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed as a reminder all
participant lines will be in the listen
only mode and there will be an
opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes should
you need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing star than zero on
your touchone phone I now hand the
conference over to Mr sanjie mantri MD
and CEO ICI lombar General Insurance
Limited thank you and over to you
sir thank
you good evening to each one of you
thank you for joining the earnings
conference call of icsl Ard General
Insurance Company Limited for quarter 1
Financial year
2025 let me give you a brief overview of
the industry Trends and developments
that we have witnessed in the uing
months post this our CFO Mr goal
balachandran will share the financial
performance of the company
or the quarter ended junee 30th
2024 during the financial year 2024 the
Indian economy served by an impressive
8.2% which is better than the expected
growth of
7.6% maintaining his position as the
fastest growing major economy globally
during quarter 1 2025 the key frequency
indicators such as toll collections GST
receipts and EV bills continue to remain
buyant manufacturing and construction
sector showed strong activ and PMI data
also highlighted robust demand and
strong export
orders however Global geopolitical
tension and uneven distribution of
domestic Monsoon can be a key risk to
the ongoing growth
momentum now talking about the Auto
industry during the quarter we have seen
decent growth in the wholesale numbers
as reported by CM With Private Car
growing at 3% two wheer at 20.4% and CV
at
7.8% this entails approximately 1
million private cars 5 million two
wheelers and4 million CVS being sold
during the
quarter however the retail numbers as
reported by F has seen muted growth for
private car at 2.5% two wheelers at
12.6% and CV at 6% for quarter 1
2025 despite relatively lower retail
sales during the quarter we expect the
onso of the festive season in the coming
months to Auger well for Auto industry
health insurance as a segment continues
to be driven by under penetration in the
retail Health business coupled with
enhanced awareness in The Last 5 Years
Health as segment is growing more than
20% cagr and we expect this trend to
persist for
2025 the commercial line of business
grew by 10.3% during the quarter fire
line of business continue to witness
pricing pressure due to impact of
discontinuance of iib
rate however with better awareness of
new age risk and continued government
focus on infrastructure development and
related capital expenditure the
commercial and business expected to do
well in coming
quarters overall from an insurance
industry standpoint we see a significant
convergence with macro and micro factors
supporting the
growth coming to the performance of
General insurance industry it delivered
a year on year gross direct premium
income growth of 13.3% for quarter 1
Financial year 202 5 x crop and mass
gdpi for the industry was at 14.8% for
the same
period we have seen quarter 1 Financial
year 2025 growth being sequentially
better than Q4 of last year and we
expect this trajectory to continue in
the coming
quarters overall the combined issue of
the industry was at 112% for financial
year
2024 as against 11 15.8% for financial
2023 for motor the combine ratio was at
11 18.5% for financial year 2024 as
against
121.1mi
rate in the the motor combined ratio for
the industry continues to remain under
pressure in our previous call we
discussed a series of Regulation
prescribed by The Authority the
regulatory environment is becoming more
cohesive and recently The Authority has
issued various circul including Master
circulars on health and General
Insurance
respectively these developments are
expected to AER well for policy holders
and the industry over the long
term now I'll speak about the business
impact for us in quarter 1 Financial
year
2025 the company's gdpi grew at 20.4%
during quarter 1 Financial year 2025
which has been higher than the industry
growth of 13.3% during the same
period let me now touch upon a
performance in key business segments
during the quarter in the commercial
line segment during quarter 1 2025 we
grew at
99.7% we continue to maintain leadership
position in segments such as engineering
liability and Marine
cargo as mentioned earlier with the fire
segment has seen prising pressure the
inherent growth continues to remain
intact despite the head means we have
maintained our market share in the fire
segment we remain Vigilant in terms of
risk selection and will continue to
monitor developments in coming quarters
in motor for quarter One Financial year
2025 we registered a growth of
26.3% reserv is industry growth of 12%
we continue to harness our strong
capabilities in this segment across
distribution underwriting claim
servicing and actal practices the
overall growth in motor segment was AED
by strong growth in Old
business the new private car business
View at
13.4% is as against CM volume growth of
3% two wheer segment registered growth
of 21% in quarter 1 Financial year 20125
in line with the CM volume growth while
the new CV segment R by 20.3% as against
CM volume growth of 7.8% during the same
period during the quarter we have
continued to maintain balanc portfolio
With Private Car two wheer and CV makes
at 51 51.5% 26% and 22.5% respectively
we also continue to build efficiency in
motor claims in fin quarter 1 2025 we
were able to survey 69.9% of our agency
and direct claims to our preferred
partner Network up from up from 56.3% in
quarter 1 Financial year
2024 with the denotification of tariff
wordings and the operational guidelines
of Master circular we expect newer
product opportunities in the motor
segment which will enable the segment to
expand further we are excited to share
that we have recently introduced
long-term product for private car and
two- wheeler
segment we stay positive on the motor
segment and a leveraging our
multi-distribution strategy to drive
growth across channels which enables us
to sustain Market leadership in the
segment the health segment view at 28.5%
in quarter 1 Financial year 2025 again
the industry growth of
16.6% in group health employer employee
segment we grew at 31 1% in quarter 1
2025 the change in the underlying
industry pricing sentiment resulted in
customers moving towards insurers and
Superior servicing capabilities helping
us to build this
portfolio for first couple of months
during the quarter R retail Health
business grew lower than our
expectation however with the launch of a
new health insurance solution growth
reached 14.4% in the month of June
overall the retail H business View at
12.6% in quarter 1 financially year
2025 compared to the industry growth of
19% as updated earlier we continue to
remain committed to invest create
differentiation and provide solutions
for the retail Health segment in this
endeavor to enhance a value proposition
we recently launched a new revolutionary
retail health insurance solution Elevate
powered by AI Elevate offers key addon
such as infinite suure infinite care
power booster jump start Etc these on
are industry first or industry best
offerings doing the further the solution
is backed by AI engine which offers
optimal coverage based on customer
Persona we launch this solution across
the country to through 200 plus events
bnan events with that agency
distribution during the quarter with
lower credit dispersement growth of a
key relationship Partners a bank of
business view by
7.5% however IC group distribution view
by 30
1.4% for quarter 1 Financial year 2025
due to strategic focus on Branch Banking
business when it comes to a relationship
across distribution we continue to deep
mine our existing Relationships by
creating new value streams and at the
same time focus on expanding
relationship by staying invested in this
channel as mentioned in the last call we
continue to stay invested in
strengthening our digital business
resultantly our customer facing digital
business due by
.7% in q1 constituting 4.9% of our
overall
business our onstop solution for all
insurance and wellness needs the IL take
care app has surprised 10 million user
downloads till date we registered a
premium of
54.5 million for the
quarter as far as servicing of customer
is concerned we continue to leverage
Solutions such as cloud-based calling
for motor claims which has enhanced a
customer experience by allowing direct
interaction with the assigned claim
manager bypassing the need for ivr
system at call center this advancement
has provided them immediate Clarity on
claim processes current status and form
resolution for the inquiries our clients
are increasingly embracing the service
selfservice capabilities of a chatbot
Ria which provides assistance across all
our Digital customer interfaces the
utilization of R for checking Health
claim statuses and downloading policy
copies for have doubled in comparison to
the previous
year during our previous call we spoke
about one is one team Vision as a part
of this initiative we continue to drive
synergies where whether it is for in
terms of one one digital one one agency
or one is one call center our Collective
efforts focused on the organization
goals has created T WIS D which are
driving Superior growth in the recent
months we will continue to consistently
Leverage The Power of one al1 team
through efficient systems and processes
driven by our teams in our previous
update we discussed our Core Business
and Technology transformation project
project or we initiated this
transformation Journey with our health
business and are now progressively
extending these efforts to our other
lines of
businesses we will remain focused on
leveraging our multi-product
multi-distribution strategy we aim to
achieve profitable growth by harnessing
data effectively ening digital
advancements and introducing new
products simultaneously we will continue
to Foster growth as one aisle one
team I will now request gopal to take
you through the financial numbers for
the Recently concluded quarter and year
thanks sanjie and uh good evening to
each one of you I will now give you a
brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter the results have been uploaded
on our on our stock exchanges and uh you
will be able to see the same getting
reflected on our website as well you can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers the gross direct
premium income of the company was at R
76.8 billion for quarter 1 fi25 as
against R 63.8 7 billion in q1 FY 24
this was a growth of 20.4% which was
higher than the industry growth of
13.3% excluding crop and Mass health
gdpi growth of the company was at
19.7% again higher than the industry
growth of 14.8% in q1
fi25 our gdpi growth during the quarter
was primarily DED by growth in the
preferred segments the overall GDP of
our Property and Casualty segment grew
by 9.7% at rupes 25.8 billion in q1 fi25
as against R 22.86 billion in q1 fi 24
on the retail side of the business GDP
of the motor segment was at rupes 23.6 n
billion in q1
fi25 as against R 18.75 billion in q1
f524 again registering a growth of
26.3% the advanc premium numbers was at
rupes 34.56 billion at June 30 2024 as
againsted R 33.3 billion as at March 31
2024 GDP of the health segment was at R
23.37% our agents which includes the
point of sale distribution count was at
13121 as on June 30 2024 up from 1 lak
128 411 as on March 31 2024 our combined
ratio was 10.3% for quarter 1
fi25 as against 13.8% for quarter 1
f524 our investment assets Rose to rupes
51.4 billion as at June 30 2024 up from
rupes 48907 billion as at March 31 2024
our investment leverage was 4.14 times
as at June 30 2024 as against 4.09 times
as at March 31 2024 investment income
was at rupes 11.28 billion in quarter 1
fi25 as against rupes 8.44 billion in
quarter 1 fi 24 the investment income
for q1 fi 24 has been revised basis the
recent iida Master circular dated May
1724 our capital gains net of
empowerment on investment assets
increased to rupes 2.8 4 billion in
quarter 1
fi25 as compared to rupes 1.23 billion
in quarter 1 fi 24 our profit before tax
grew by
48.8% at rupes 7.74 billion in q1 fi25
as against rupes 5.2 billion in quarter
one of the last year consequently profit
after tax also grew about a similar
number at
48.7% at rupees 5.80 billion in q1 fi25
as against R 3.9 billion in q1 fi 24
return on average equity for quarter one
this year was 19.1% as against 14.7% in
q1 last year solvency ratio was at 2.56
times at June 30 2024 as againsted 2.62
times as at March 31 2024 and this
continues to be higher than the minimum
regulatory requirement of 1.5 times as I
conclude we remain steadfast in our
commitment to driving profitable growth
creating sustainable value and
safeguarding the interest of of our
policy holders at all times I would like
to thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take any questions that you may have
thank you thank you very much we will
now begin the question and answer
session anyone who wishes to ask a
question may press star and one on the
ATT touchone phone if you wish to remove
yourself from the question CU you may
press star and
two participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question que
assembles our first question is from the
line of shria shiwani from CSA please go
ahead hi uh thank you for the opportun
opportunity and congratulations on a
good set of numbers uh sir I basically
have a question on the motor segment um
uh and you guys have delivered quite
well particularly in the first two
months of of this quarter um some color
if you can give about I know you've said
that more growth came from old Vehicles
than new vehicles I'm not sure if I
caught that right if you can help me
with that second uh the the thing with
the motor segment is that the motor TP
book has seen quite a strong growth for
OD is the fastest for you but TP growth
was also very strong given that
competition in this segment has been de
growing also the loss ratio or the
reserving triangles for a lot of
competition for FY 24 saw a bit of
versing so is there any dramatic shift
in the industry Dynamics or the
competitive landscape or any color that
you can give us give to us about the
motor segment and whether we can sustain
this 20 25 plus percentage growth rate
in the motor segment that will be useful
thank
you hi hi thanks sh uh yes clearly not
couple of months I think the full
quarter the team has been able to do
pretty well as far as motor segment is
concerned but look uh we always
maintained a very steady line that being
a multi-line multi-product company in
that sense uh we will go where we
believe there is value uh at some point
of time if we were if we go back in time
in terms of our quarter one quarter two
call last year you had seen that we had
retracted significantly because it was
not making uh commercial sense to pursue
what was going on uh we spoke about the
industry number for financial year 2024
there is a bit of a semblance in terms
of of again the loss ratio which is
there we see an overall industrywide
some improvement while still it stays
concerning uh we were able to leverage
that uh part of it uh with respect to
the new and old uh new sales per as I
said the f number has given a very muted
number but overall supplies have
increased and that should hold good in
the uing quarter when you have festive
season uh coming in for us again from
Deep mining we were able to do a much
better better job on uh getting the old
book so you're right uh our new grew at
X percentage or maybe around 16 17% but
the old book has gone at almost 33% so
that's what has given uh value for us as
a company uh question on the last one
and I then leave to gopal if he wants to
add something is this sustainable I mean
this kind of a market share Gap I don't
think is sustainable will be a right
thing uh but we will continue to stay
vigilant if there is a value on the
table for us you will see us uh
operating with same intensity it's not
that when we were not uh you know
gaining market share we were not doing
what was required we'll continue doing
the right things and hopefully the
outcome will fall in place uh but yes uh
on motor over the segment we continue to
remain committed as an entity goal you
like to add something yeah I think only
I'll just kind of add on to say that uh
I think the good news is there seems to
be semblance playing out in motor as a
segment I think which is what we kind of
put out also as a part of the opening
remarks to say that directionally
possibly the combin ratio for the
industry looks to be kind of as I said
uh going down almost about 3 or 4% when
you look at it on a full year basis this
is obviously a trend that we will watch
for even for the subsequent quarters and
link to this is your last question that
you asked in terms of what has been the
loss experience or let's say the loss
ratios for the industry let's say Vis
what has it kind of worked out for us uh
honestly I'm sure each companies will
have their own approach to write risks
in the way they would want to source and
the outcomes is more a reflection of the
thought processes that they would have
had taken in their respective companies
so very difficult to comment on the the
way the reserving triangle disclosures
are moving for those players but at
least from so far as our uh standpoint
is concerned from an IC Lombard
standpoint I think we continue to stay
prudent in our approach to reserving and
even if you recollect what we have been
talking through since the last few
quarters is on motor as a category we
have said the loss ratio band at which
we would be kind of largely comfortable
at on an overall basis has been between
65 to
67% and within that on own damage we
have generally talked about the loss
ratio staying in the range of 60 to 65
and third party in the range of let's
say 65 to 70 uh so that's largely the
kind of loss ratio band that we have
been kind of largely working with and at
this point of time given the point that
sanjiv made in terms of ability to kind
of go after micro segmentation and doing
the right right risk selection we
believe I think we we are kind of pretty
much poised to stay around those loss
ratio bands but obviously it's all a
function of what kind of business mix
that we write at the end of the day sure
sure and so just last one comment is
there is there is there are you guys
seeing any benefit from the motor
vehicle act in sense of are you seeing
faster claim intimation is there some
change in the industry Dynamics from
that persp
uh no no absolutely sure early days but
we do see uh overall on a you know on a
sequential basis uh claim
ination uh on an faster note than what
it used to be uh but uh can we be
conclusive about it as yet no but the
overall early signs are positive in the
direction that also is well for the
industry not only us yeah yeah that's
useful thank you so much thank
you thank you the next question is from
the line of mukar Lada from Nama wealth
management please go ahead uh hi uh good
evening thank you for taking my question
and uh congratulations on a great set of
numbers so a couple of things uh first
uh you know I know it's early days but
maybe you can talk a little bit about
the uh Health product what's the kind of
numbers that we seeing and uh you know
what sort of uh what what are you sort
of building in in your mind as a Target
uh for uh you know this this this year
and uh second uh you've done very well
on the investment income side so I'm not
uh I'm not sure whether you gave this
number out or not but what is the
capital gain amount and uh if you can
split the investment income in capital
gains and normal gains and then in the
opening remarks you had mentioned about
uh the numbers in for uh private car two
wheeler and CV if you could just repeat
the CV number what is it for the
industry and what is it for us so those
would be my question thanks a lot so uh
I will cly maduka thanks for your
question uh I will speak on the health
uh product and then I'll ask uh gopal to
share with your retails or investment
income as well as the private car and
two wheeler that you have shot uh again
it's been a uh thought through process
for us we be been talking on health more
so on the retail Health side in a very
big way uh as a team we've launched this
product Elevate uh supremely excited in
terms of the way it has got received uh
by the market uh uh across channels and
Partners at this point of time uh number
wise probably we'll wait till it comes
to the end of the quarter too as you
rightly said in your question itself
early days uh but uh what I can tell all
of you on the call that the it has got
received in terms of multiple industry
first that we put across uh uh we do see
uh significant traction and uh as a team
all of us are very excited as to where
it can take us in the health segment and
yes this should be one of the critical
steps to make our journey more
concrete so as I said you know in couple
of calls that we have done that our
efforts uh on health had many times have
not reflected the output uh hopefully we
are seeking through this some
convergence on that uh as an entity is
all I can say now I'll hand it over to
gopal to take the other two question of
you so maybe I'll go in the reverse
sequence I'll take the third one which
is relatively easier I think we put out
you're right we put that as a part of
the opening remarks just to kind of rate
the mix between overall motor on private
car two wheeler and CV that mixes at
51.5% is Private Car 26% is two wheelers
and the CV mix is
22.5% uh to your other question on the
investment sorry sorry goal gopal I
wanted your the number of new CV growth
was what for the industry and what what
is it for CM numb okay what the CM
numbers okay c number CM numbers for uh
Private Car two wheeler and CV for this
quarter Private Car growth was 3% two
wheer is
20.4% and CV is at 7.8%
and what is it for us that 20 uh for the
CV for us CV is at about
20% got
it uh now coming back to your second
question on terms of what is the split
between the overall investment income I
think again we kind of called that out
as a part of the uh opening transcript
uh see the capital gain numbers for this
quarter this is quarter one of the
current year is at 2.84
billion this number in quarter 1 of last
year was 1.23
billion got it all right thanks and all
the best thanks maduka thank
you thank you a reminder to all the
participants if you wish to register for
a question please press star and
one the next question is from the line
of sanket GAA from avenders Park please
go
ahead uh yeah uh thank than you thank
you for the opportunity uh uh see my my
my first question is on on the the
reasons what led to that uh significant
Improvement or decent Improvement in the
Opex ratio because if I look outside
commissions uh you you you your overall
Opex has declined by 7 to 8 percentage
year on year so so where this saving has
come easy because because we have
focused on Old versus new vehicle has
that played a role in significant
Improvement the opic ratio that that
that was my first question just wanted
to understand what led to it and how
sustainable it is going ahead and and
the second question what I had is that
when you do long-term uh new longterm
what you launching private cars and two
two wheelers uh just just wanted to
understand from accounting point of view
it is recognized on cash basis or or it
is one byn uh uh for for other than the
uh new new TP what you write for three
years and five years and and lastly my
question is on
you said that non bank has has seen a
growth issue which is even reflected in
personal accident cover sorry personal
acent cover growth which is declined
year on year for the quarter so so is it
is it because the major Bank channels
like GFC or AES have slowed down our
business and how do you think it to play
out going ahead yeah these are my
questions okay so uh think than uh with
respect to the uh uh uh with respect to
the Opex part that you're referring to
uh definitely configuration of the
portfolio has played a role there's no
doubt about it uh the growth of old uh
has definitely helped us in overall
averaging our cost uh so you're
absolutely right and besides this even
the growth in ghi which comes on a
relatively lower OPC which we have grown
as a business at almost
31.1% has played a role some bit of a
little bit of very micro but small
number of crop also has got booked on
the inal basis but I wouldn't say that
that has changed the Opex uh it's
largely driven by uh the nature of
business in which it has got done
whether it's sustainable see this it's a
very Dynamic situation we have a
regulatory requirement that we need to
manage our expense of management below
30% we would will stay committed uh at
the same time to dynamically operate and
ensure that the profit pools are taken
care of we would take calls that are
appropriate in the interest of the
you know company uh so I wouldn't go and
say that it's all sustainable but uh
some way or the other yes we will seek
efficiency and that is the direction
that we'll operate on with respect to
the bank of the long-term piece I would
request gopal to speak uh on the non
Banker Channel which is non IC Bank
channel that we are referring to we have
a larger relationship which is given by
nbfcs and the overall secure part we
have seen in the market that the disb
has gone down because of the changes in
the regulations for them uh that has
impacted our sourcing uh else we remain
very committed to this business plan it
has been a key value driver for us as an
organization as in when the overall
disbursement improves we will be we will
be there you know present with the
relationship to drive our own market
share with them and on the long-term
part and on the second second question
sanket uh pretty much similar to the
same prescription as you rightly
mentioned whatever is true for the new
private car or new two-wheeler
prescription the same prescription is
what we are following with respect to
the long-term offering that we do for
the rest of the businesses as well got
it got it and just on the Opex part just
just wanted to see I understand the
ratio Improvement is because of little
more ghi and crop um but uh absolute
decline in the cost is is the point I
was more focused on that that that it
declined by S and a half 8 percentage so
so so is it largely attributable to the
fact that your retail Health growth was
lower and old old component has
increased in the motor just wanted to
understand that one and if that is the
strategy going then then we can see
structural Improvement in The opic Rao
yeah so sank again I think this is
something that keeps coming to us every
quarter right in terms of uh where is
the directional movement on the overall
Excellence numbers I would again kind of
keep reiterating the fact that end of
the day as an institution what I think
everyone should be kind of largely
watching out for is the combin isue
outcome uh because again rightly
mentioned by you businesses obviously
gets impacted by different mix different
growth levels within a particular
segment and each of them have obviously
its own nuances and Dynamics with
respect to the overall cost of
acquisition having said that I think if
you look at generally quarter 1
obviously tends to be slightly lower
because the relative proportion of
commercial lines insurances tends to be
higher so hence to that extent there is
an element of a cost of acquisition that
plays out but having said that I think
what we have also been able to achieve
is the relative efficiency and the
productivity gain on even motor as a
category in terms of the top line coming
back to us at the acceptable level of
cost of acquisition and again the point
that we made out within that segment
the growth has also kind of largely
stemm from what sanjie mentioned the old
growth in in motor has been 33% plus so
obviously as the older portfolio grows
faster the relative cost of acquisition
equally is lower so and that's something
that we kind of keep moderating if you
ask us what will be the directional
Trend that this expense ratios will take
I think the only thing that we would
kind of call out to say is at all points
of time we stand committed to staying
within the threshold of 30% very
difficult to pull out and say that uh
what will we finally end the number with
the Endeavor is obviously to kind of
make sure that we operate within that
overall objective uh so hence lots of
moving part very very difficult to call
out a particular thing to say that what
has led to the overall efficiency in the
expense numbers got it sorry to
interrupt Mr God may we request you
return to the question CU for followup
questions as there are several other
participants waiting for the thank you
so much
we'll take the next question from the
line of Aditi josi from JP Morgan please
go
ahead uh thank you for dising my
question so I have three questions so uh
sir can you please help us understand on
the group health side uh what are the
competitive Dynamics you are seeing and
also in terms of pricing Trend that was
observed and your outlook as in going
forward in the coming quarters how do
you see the health insurance pricing
both in the retail segment as well as in
the group segment that is the employer
employee uh the second question is
related to the combined ratio guidance
uh we came up in the last call uh
suggesting that the Improvement in the
combin ratio might be faster than the
previous expectations uh but the in the
first quarter it was around 102% level
versus uh
10.5% that we were expecting so sir uh
can you expect can you please help us
understand if that is what you continue
to think and uh if so then what would
lead to that faster than expected
Improvement and then just the third
question is on the uh uh in the
underwriting profit uh segment wise
there was a significant Improvement in
miscellaneous group and corporate so can
you please suggest what this precisely
is thank you
so uh so ad I think uh maybe I will go
in the same
sequence uh I think uh this is let me
start with the corporate Health uh again
pretty much similar to what sanjie
explained on the motor side I think as a
thought process I think when markets
have been quite aggressive we have
obviously tried to take a guarded stance
but continue to stay invested in our
distribution SL servicing capabilities
the same thought process is what we have
you know even on the corporate health I
think Market did see signs of stress for
some time at least for the in the last
few years that seems to be kind of
coming back which is why even as a part
of the opening remarks we did call out
to say that there seems to be kind of uh
pricing discipline coming back
particularly from players who have been
very aggressive in writing this
particular segment so obviously now the
fact that let's say pricing discipline
is happening on corporate Health that
obviously is giving us an opportunity
which is why as a segment I think we
have been able to kind of outgrow the
market at an underwriting outcome which
is to our liking which also kind of
responds to the last question that you
asked in the context of let's say the
corporate SL miscellaneous uh group
segments in terms of the absolute
outcome on the underwriting side uh on
the retail I think obviously uh one
keeps looking for what is the quality of
the book that we want to write I think
we kind of stay to the loss ratio
thresholds that we have generally spoken
about which has been around 70% numbers
on the retail health I think that that
loss ratio band is something that we
would obviously want to kind of stay uh
focused on and the fact that we have
been able to kind of launch this new
health insurance solution uh will
obviously kind of Aid uh in terms of the
loss ratio outcomes that we are kind of
expecting for the rest of the year as
well and obviously we continue to
monitor the portfolio in terms of its
development we believe we have fairly
priced for the the risk features that we
have kind of launched as a part of this
solution but as I said at the end of the
year uh at the end of the day we would
obviously want to see that particular
segment operating in that loss ratio
range of about 70% on the last one on
the second question in terms of the
combined ratio trajectory I think pretty
much I think what we have what we are
seeing is obviously a directional
Improvement in the way we have been able
to kind of exhibit our combin ratio
outcomes but again as we keep saying
this has to be looked at in the context
of the industry movement on combin uh
the good news is again what we called
out at least basis public disclosure on
the full year numbers for
fi4 has been relatively better than fi23
by almost 4 percentage points
Improvement in Combined for the overall
market now obviously if this kind of a
trend line continues and within that
motor has seen almost again a 3 to 4%
improvement from an overall industry
standpoint if this trend line was to
kind of further continue for the rest of
the year I think we believe that we
should be able to kind of stick to our
exit quarter 4 combined ratio thought
process that we have of about 101.5 I
think we should be able to kind of get
to that trajectory by the end of the
year so that's in response to the second
one the last one I think again I will
again I will keep kind of saying that an
absolute underwriting outcome in itself
may not mean much particularly when you
look at it in a quarterly context
because as we know that whenever you end
up doing relatively higher growth this
could be across any segment the relative
cost of acquisition comes and hits you
up FR uh but all that we can say safe
for sure is hence you always keep urging
to keep looking at the combined ratio
numbers the good news is as I said the
the fact that we have been able to write
a risk portfolio which is to our
underwriting outcome and hence to that
extent the combined ratio trajectory for
the company as a whole has been in line
with what we would want to see ourselves
that uh just a clarification and what
categories come under the miscellaneous
in this uh uh in this disclosure please
so anything which is not covered by the
rest of the segments for which there is
a separate disclosure that is put out
all of them come as a part of the
miscellanous
segment yes that will include the
engineering part in it yeah yeah yeah
yeah so all those separate segments that
have been specifically put put out in
terms of regulatory prescriptions have
been put out separately anything which
is not there as a part of those SE uh
separately laid out requirement they
will all form a part of miscelaneous
that is
correct okay thank you
thank you ladies and gentlemen in order
to ensure that the management is able to
address questions from all the
participants in the conference please
restrict your questions to TU
participant if you have any follow off
questions you may rejoin the queue the
next question is from the line of prayes
Jan from modal please go
ahead yeah hi good evening everyone
congrats on the great set of numbers uh
so on the health ratio loss ratio front
uh know there is an increase from 78.7%
to
83.6% what is this really reflective of
in terms of uh M or are there any
adverse trends that we've seen in the
quarter and how should we think about
this that would be my first one uh
second is on the motor strategy there in
you know you spoken about the older
vehicles growth has been stronger
generally you know OEM growth OEM
channel would have has been our strength
and that generally drives our growth in
the new vehicle business so what
differently we've done to grow the uh
retail the the older vehicle channel
it's digital where we become more
competitive or it's through the agents
Channel how has this kind of come across
and whether that's sustainable and
lastly on the mot T price side you know
with this kind of loss ratios trending
do we really envisage price coming this
year or even for that matter if sustains
anytime soon
even M price should we should work with
those
questions okay uh uh thanks pish uh for
your question uh on the health side in
particular where we see relatively
increased loss ratio I think gopal in a
way also spoke about it as to where we
expect it to be around there are two
segments to it which is retail health
and then the other part is the group
health uh but that being said there is
no denial of the fact that we have seen
relative increase in uh frequency uh
which has impacted the uh uh loss is
overall and from what also we are aware
of it has been the
uh it has been at the industry level and
it has it is something which is
witnessed across is what we are
understanding whether this trend will be
secular and we be there quarter 2
typically has a elevated loss ratio
because of the monsoon that comes in
there are vector bone diseases you know
which can have an impact uh over on the
this uh but for us uh since we have you
know also launched the product which is
expected to do well I think the mix
should also play out overcoming quarters
to help us in rebalancing our book uh uh
and we remain committed to the overall
segment and more so on the retail Health
which we want to you know continue to
invest in grow so that's first part as
far as health is concerned on motor per
has a strategy where it stands new and
old so it's not that the new part which
we have shared the numbers also has not
done well for us we have uh done well on
the new side but it is the growth of old
which is also significantly which is
exceeded new both uh sections have done
well but definitely old has grown at
Double the rate of what new has grown
for as a company and that has helped us
rebalancing it uh agency also has done
well and other channels also from
wherever we are able to Source motor uh
like broking Channel also has done well
in terms of uh overall strategy we will
be we are deeply entrenched in every
single section whether it is Private Car
two wheer and Commercial Vehicle we will
continue to explore opportunities there
are a lot of work that has been done by
our actu as well as underwriting in
terms of further segmenting the market
to create wide spaces and see if we can
do further business in that on motor
hike the last part that you uh have
spoken about look I mean this is
something which comes under the
regulatory require envirment we continue
to pursue um because at the industry
level there's still need uh in some
segments to see increase and maybe there
are some segments that there can be a
decrease also on third party to overall
rebalance the book and it is not only
for for growth it is also for us as an
entity if that pricing Factor comes in
since it is regulated it will help us to
further expand our Market that's what it
is PR from our side yeah but this
clarification on motor part so have we
you know like in the last 6 to n months
got more competitive in terms of pricing
or what has been the change in the
approach of our which has you know one
obviously the industry Trends have been
phable but even from our side what what
changes we have done with respect to
pricing which has does does that play a
role yes obviously the there is an
element of pricing but we have continued
to be in a similar journey to be very
honest others have who were far more
aggressive recalibrated it and that gain
also has ured to us it is not that we
have you
know uh gone you know dramatically on
the price cut side we have stayed
moderate in the zone which is we always
been talking to each one of you it's
just that the others who were uh being
far more aggressive in the market uh
have you
know gone ahead and you know taken some
more of control in terms of numbers so
that's where it stands it's we've been
consistent and also moderating whichever
way we want to acquire you know in the
market that we want to acquire we have
done what is required to stay valid in
those another piece which is there is
the PPN Network that we have started
leveraging very extensively and today we
would be on the agency and direct side
we've got almost 70% of our claims which
are being you know processed at the PPN
Network which is the preferred partner
Network that we have uh that drive
significant efficiency also for us
overall and helps us in the motor
profitability go thank you and all the
thank you thank you the next question is
from the line of nides from invest Tech
please go ahead
uh thanks for the opportunity so my my
question is on health insurance product
uh what is the underwriting process or
philosophy in that product even that
pricing is quite attractive so how how
are we controlling
underwriting at the at the customer
origination level and what are the
reduction rates for that for that
product so pricing obviously is a
function of uh our own modeling that we
have done and uh uh clearly uh I would
say that we are aware of uh what we are
doing further details in terms of uh uh
what is the rejection and all I mean
honestly we would not like to share that
uh but yes the business is uh since
there a decent pull besides the you know
launching this product it does give us
the leeway of underwriting what we
believe uh will make sense and the ones
which will not we wouldn't uh so it's at
a simple level and if you see the
Constructor of the product which is very
important if you all have not seen it
you must go through it's a it's it's a
very modular product where the features
are available as add on so it's up to
the customers whether they want to pick
it up and all so there is a risk pricing
element that has got created which
otherwise was not the case so it was one
shoe fit all kind of a product which
will say that this is what's available
but in this we've gone through a chasis
model we'll say that this is the core uh
which you will sell and then there are
features if they if they suit your
require you must opt for it so it avoids
Miss selling and at the same time it
allows us to price the risk
appropriately sure sure that's it from
my thank you thanks s thanks thank you
the next question is from the line of NJ
toshal from UPS Securities please go
ahead congrat said uh so three questions
first the of the duration of the book
and the team we should work with second
is on the retentions have been gen1
retentions are lower so commissions
should have been a little lower is it
the motor the mix which has come up and
driving the higher little higher
commissions ver is last V1 and third is
more towards today's incident of the uh
the global it outage wanted to
understand any cyber Insurance uh from
the Cyber Insurance perspective have the
are we see any that or how could we want
think about it the is very small but
just wanted some thoughts
here maybe I take the last one
first um so I think obviously too early
to call out whether there because it's
like a cyclone happening and can be kind
of estimate what will be the impact of
losses that has hit our book U so
obviously it will take a while for us if
at all uh there is any impact so far as
claims is concerned uh but again just
kind of going back to the underwriting
discipline I I think what we have tried
to do from an underwriting standpoint is
obviously to kind of write and reselect
books which we think will be within our
uh underwriting appetite and hence and
end of the day whatever underwriting we
do we are in the business of paying
claims and therefore to that extent if
there is genuinely a claim and obviously
to that extent we will honor those
commitments uh but too early to call out
but obviously maybe in the subsequent
quarter we will be able to give you a
much better update in terms of where we
are consequent to this outage that one
would have possibly seen um to your
first point I think in terms of what is
the duration of the book the duration of
the book currently is at about 5.48
years uh this is something if you
recollect I think we have been obviously
kind of taking advantage of the higher
interest rate regime over the last
couple of years and that again kind of
Aur very well uh in terms of the uh
portfolio uh interest approvals and
that's kind of pretty much playing and
we are kind of well positioned to uh
capitalize the opportunity depending on
how the interestate Cycles move in the
market
uh so that's what we keep doing it's not
just in this period I think even over
years when we have seen periods of uh
High interest regime during those times
we have obviously tried to kind of go
long and as possibly the cycle of
interest rates starts to reverse we have
been able to see the benefit of maybe a
higher realization getting kind of
approved to us in terms of capital gains
and obviously till that time higher
interest acrs um so that's that's that's
the response to the duration of the
portfolio on the second question on if I
if I got you right on the commission
ratios again as I kind of explained
earlier I think uh at the end of the day
what we will be largely Guided by I
think this is something that you will
keep hearing from us we will be largely
Guided by the combined ratio objective
which will obviously a function of what
is it that that one sees on the loss
ratio and what is it that one sees on
the expense of management uh to call out
one over the other honestly uh for us
may not be the right thing because
that's the inherent nature of the
business that we are in we will we are
in a multiproduct multi-distribution we
Source different type of businesses and
therefore each business mix we have an
outcome which will be very different uh
so hence again just to reiterate We
Stand committed to the trajectory of the
decline declining combined ratio that we
have spoken about and at the end of the
year assuming the market continues to uh
kind of show improved trajectory We
Stand committed to see a combin ratio
which is quarter 4 exit of about 101.5
that thank you thank you so much all
thanks thank thank
you the next question is from the line
of ainash Singh from MK Global please go
ahead yeah hi thanks for the opportunity
couple of questions uh the first one if
you can help again on motor uh that you
explained that share of f has gone up I
mean is it uh you know how it has
planned out in various distribution
Channel I mean agent or is it again
gaining share from you know other
players at the OEM dealer point or is it
uh you know something to do with the new
uh you know corporate broker or online
broker TI you have done that's one
second is I mean if I look at the mot
third party you know loss ratio of 69%
for the quarter it looks I mean so is it
just based on this quarter or like
there's some support coming because I
mean if I see for in Industry you are
the only one who has in motor TP for if
22 or 23 you have not taken any kind of
a re so far uh so is the 69% has now
getting some support from the Rel
or this quarter only and if you can give
some kind of performer idea that how if
I mean in the in days when the reserve
discounting is allowed how the 69% would
typically look
thanks uh so I maybe I'll take the
second second one and maybe I'll kind of
respond to the couple of questions on TP
loss ratios and maybe the related impact
on the indas front and let me start with
the reverse order I think again uh it
indas for us is work in progress uh and
as I have been saying even in the
earlier calls I think we will come back
to the market at appropriate time to
talk about what exactly will be the the
relative impact when we transition to uh
the inds from a discounting of Reserve
standpoint but one element which I will
again keep reating is irrespective of
whether it is Indian Gap or whether it
is uh transition to indas the underlying
economic profit of the business that we
are writing is not undergoing a change
uh so it's more a reflection of what
profits you see under the current
accounting prescription Vis let's say a
a change accounting prescription that
could be the only Dynamics but the core
under underwriting objective or let's
say the economic outcome will be
something that we will be kind of
largely working towards uh in terms of
its outcome specific numbers I think
we'll wait for a couple of quarters to
come back on the third party loss ratio
savash I think again which is why one
called out at the beginning to say what
is the range that one is comfortable
with in terms of uh the third party loss
ratio outcomes but having said that I
think you're absolutely right uh does it
make sense to look at the number more on
a quarterly basis is something that we
again keep kind of talking about I think
ideally you understand all of you
understand this far better particularly
on third party this is a segment which
you have to look at numbers over long
years so hence uh the range is something
that we have talked about and that's
what we will possibly end up doing in
terms of the mix uh of the business that
we write within Private Car two-wheeler
and commercial vehicles and that's what
we kind of keep revisiting forget about
the numbers that we put out on a
quarterly basis to all of you internally
for us it's it's on a everyday basis in
terms of the way how we kind of res
select portfolios between Private Car
two wheeler and commercial vehicles so
hence I think the range just to kind of
rate rate on third party we what we will
be comfortable is within a range of 65
to 70 and obviously the experiences of
the third party book has to be looked at
over longer cycles and S also also on
the motor in terms of the old part uh as
I had mentioned also in the previous
question that were asked uh our growth
has been across channels clearly there
is no way the old can grow at a double
the rate of new if we don't have better
retentions coming from D from our dealer
Network so that also has played out uh
and that being said even the agency as
well as the website and booking business
has contributed but it is not something
which is that one out of the few which
has delivered it been overall a very
very comprehensive wellth thought plan
uh again uh it's a question of where we
believe uh we are able to derive value
for sourcing if we see that over coming
quarters not playing out we may choose
to stay where we are so these are all
very Dynamic calls that we have to take
as an entity on a realtime basis and
fortunately as far as uh Private Car in
particular which is almost 51% of our
motor book the ability to read the own
damage numbers is pretty you know
current and we don't have to wait to see
it play out these calls will take on a
virtually month to month
basis okay yeah thanks thank you thanks
a thanks a thank
you we take our next question from the
line of suim data from Ambit please go
ahead thanks for the opportunity my
first question is on the recent IA
change with respect to commissions for
long-term motor policies now the
commission limit has been done away with
so just wanted your observation that
what how do you see this playing out in
the industry and what impact could this
have that that would be the first one
the second one is when I look at the
quarterly numbers there appears to be a
provision release of around 355 million
now there was a a lower kind of
provision release last year in the first
quarter as well just wanted to
understand why does this keep happening
in the first quarter and is
something that we need to be cognizant
of going forward that would be my second
question and lastly on the health
insurance P if you could uh you know
help us understand what is the profile
of customer that you are targeting with
this new product and what was the retail
versus group loss ratio breakdown for
this thank
you yeah so maybe
uh uh I'll will go in the same
sequence uh on the irdi recent
guidelines on accounting for long-term I
think for at this point of time we would
not want to kind of uh uh put out
specifically in terms of what the impact
could be primarily because uh at this
stage as you all know the regulator
regulator has rightly kind of put forth
the uh implementation of this to be
deferred for couple of quarters uh and
in the interim obviously industry and
the regulator will work to see how what
finally and in which shape and form does
this guideline eventually translate into
uh so honestly maybe at that point of
time once we have a finality to the way
how this will get played out is when we
will call out in terms of what impact
would it have on the overall book uh to
your second point supratim if I got you
correct this 355 million provision are
you referring it in the context of uh
any specific line
item yeah it's the provision to for
demun Investments understood okay all
right so which is what I was just
wanting to try to understand uh so
obviously that's again a function of uh
what does one see uh we do have our own
uh uh impairment policies which is more
internal uh uh that we have kind of put
in place and that obviously gets uh
assessed on a time to time basis what
effectively happens is in case if you
find that a particular value of a stock
as has reached a price which we believe
is right then to that extent obviously
we take calls in terms of making an exit
and whenever we take calls to exit maybe
that particular stock at that point of
time this is more an accounting uh
reflection as in at that point of time
one would see a reversal of the
provision for empowerment happening in
the quarter in which the call to exit
the stock would have been taken and
correspondingly there would be an
element of capital gain as one would
have possibly seen given the fact that
we have seen the value of the stock
reaching a price at which we are
comfortable to take that call uh so
hence so there is no unusual or specific
uh instance that one has seen
specifically happening in quarter one
that is more coincidental than uh
because as I said it's more a call that
the investment SL the treasury function
does basis individual stock that one
picks uh to your point on the last one
which is with respect to the health
insurance segment in terms of what
profile of customers that we want to uh
uh underwrite obviously is across bands
again if you look at the uh entry age of
this particular Health Insurance
Solutions that we have that's again
something that we have been able to kind
of expand I think it starts from 18 and
it kind of goes on to whichever age
limit that one would want to kind of uh
get in as a part of the uh portfolio
underwriting so therefore the Endeavor
for it is not that we would want to kind
of pick and choose any particular
category of customers our Endeavor is I
think again what sanjie mentioned I
think the good part of the solution is
what we want to create as an offering is
something that will be more unique and
personal to an individual and hence to
that extent whatever is the right health
insurance solution for that customer or
that or that individual is what we would
want to kind of recommend as a part of
the uh solution and that's the kind of
profile of customers that one would want
to write and that could cut across
various age groups that could cut across
various geographies that could cut
across various limits of some insured
expectations because each customer will
have its own expectations so that's what
I would kind of live it with and finally
just on the loss ratios front I think
again as we have spoken quarterly
numbers again may not be largely
reflective of what the portfolio
experience of the overall book will be
again just to reiterate the corporate
health or the group health book is
something that we would see on a full
year basis at a loss ratio range
anywhere between 94 to 95% that's the
range that we have spoken about even in
the past and Retail Health inity again
we have spoken about a loss ratio about
7 just one last one on obviously the
target which we want to have is healthy
lives it's very difficult and I can
share with you quickly if you only ride
younger population the persistency drops
because they have a tendency to move
away if they have some other expenses to
incur so it's a healthy mix of young as
well as relatively older population uh
is the mix that we have it idea is to
over all source as much as possible
healthy life that is the criteria that
it works on each one of it comes with it
own set of
challenges got it no that that's very
fair you just one clarification so you
have called out that the relative
increase in claim frequency within the
health insurance portfolio now was that
at a retail level or a group health
level so see I tell you it's important
to understand whether we write group or
we write retail the unit when it's comes
and reports s is a individual customer
himself the mode of writing is of no
consequence so the elevated frequency
would come uh at a category level not at
a you know whether it is individual or
group uh I hope am I you're able to
understand it's always the category that
we are seeing more people falling sick
which manner they'll come whe they'll
come from group of retail is part of the
process of how the product of health
insurance has been picked up by
them on this thank you yeah thanks
thanks thank you ladies and gentlemen we
would take that as a last question for
today I would now like to hand the
conference over to Mr sanjie mantri for
closing comments I I great I think thank
you so much for joining in and wish you
all a great quarter to and look forward
to connecting with you individually as
and when you are visiting our offices
all the best thank you so much thank
you thank you on behalf of ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited that
concludes this conference thank you for
joining us you may now disconnect your l